https://www.atsa.com/privacy

This website uses cookies to give you the best experience when you visit our website. By continuing to use this website, you consent to our use of these cookies. Learn more: https://www.atsa.com/privacy
Home
ATSA Privacy Policy
PRIVACY POLICY OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR THE TREATMENT OF SEXUAL ABUSERS
Adopted and Effective as of September18, 2018
This Privacy Policy (this “Privacy Policy” or “Policy”) explains how the Association for the Treatment of Sexual Abusers, Inc.  (“ATSA”) may gather, collect, record, hold, distribute or otherwise use any information or data from any user, including without limitation from any ATSA member or non-ATSA member (each a “User”; collectively “Users”), arising out of any such User’s use of ATSA’s website at http://www.atsa.com/ or any User’s receipt, access or other use of any other program, platform, material, newsletter, products or services that are provided by ATSA (hereinafter collectively referred to as a “ATSA Site”).
Each User confirms and agrees that by accessing or otherwise using any ATSA Site, the User has automatically agreed to be bound by all of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If a User does not wish his/her information to be used pursuant to this Privacy Policy, or if the User otherwise does not agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, than such User should not access or use any ATSA Site.
1. COLLECTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION
During a User’s use of any ATSA Site, ATSA may collect and/or  retain the following (hereinafter referred to as the User’s “personal identifiable information”):
(i)information or other data about the User, such as but not limited to the following: User’s name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, demographics, work/education history, ethics complaints, professional licenses, professional referral information and other personal data that may be relevant to customer support;
(ii)any content or other data that a User may upload, distribute, publish or otherwise use via the Site; or
(iii)any feedback, information or other data about a User’s use, or the results of a User’s use, of any ATSA Site.
It is ATSA’s policy to use a User’s personally identifiable information in compliance with the then applicable version of ATSA’s Code of Ethics, as ATSA may adopt from time to time and at any time  (hereinafter referred to as the “ATSA Code of Ethics”).
All of a User’s personally identifiable information that ATSA collects may be used for any or all of the following purposes by or on behalf of ATSA, subject, however, to ATSA’s compliance with the ATSA Code of Ethics (hereinafter collectively referred to as the “Intended Uses”):
(i)for ATSA’s internal administration and record keeping purposes;
(ii)to provide User with proper access to and use of any ATSA Site and/or  any of the features or functionalities of any other products or services offered, sponsored or otherwise made available by ATSA, including without limitation any of ATSA’s websites, conferences, list serves, referral lists, or membership databases (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ATSA Services”);
(iii)to provide User with any other marketing or promotional material, information or notices about any ATSA Site, any ATSA Services, or any other events offered, sponsored, or otherwise made available by or on behalf of ATSA;
(iv)to share with any of ATSA’s vendors, suppliers, independent contractors, consultants, or other industry partners of ATSA (“ATSA Partners”) in order to assist ATSA in developing, providing, operating and/or maintaining any ATSA Sites or any ATSA Services;
(v)to provide User with marketing or promotional material, information or notices regarding any features or functionalities of any products or services of any ATSA Partners or any other events offered, sponsored, or otherwise made available by or on behalf any ATSA Partners;
(vi)to provide User with any other information about any other products, services, events, functions, or items offered, sponsored, or otherwise made available by any governmental agencies, other non-profit entity, or any other party which ATSA believes may be relevant to the User; or
(vii)for any other lawful purpose.
ATSA does not intentionally share personally identifiable information about any User with third parties without a User’s consent, provided, however, each User understands and approves that ATSA has the right to share any and all of a User’s personal identifiable information: (i) for any the Intended Uses (as defined herein); (ii) with a third party (including without limitation ATSA Partners) to perform any features or functions that User requests through any ATSA Site; (iii) to the extent it becomes necessary to comply with applicable laws or to enforce ATSA’s rights; (iv) with any business partners or affiliates of ATSA, including, but not limited to, ATSA Partners, for any of the Intended Uses noted above in this Privacy Policy; and/or (v) to the extent, and pursuant to, the terms of any other agreement that ATSA may have with a User.
In the event a User has provided  ATSA with personally identifiable information such as that discussed above, and thereafter a User does not want to continue to directly receive further email communications from ATSA, the User must send an email message to office@atsa.com stating that the User no longer wants to receive email communications directly from ATSA (“Opt Out”). Once ATSA has received that User’s  request to Opt Out, ATSA will use commercially reasonable efforts, in a commercially reasonable time period, to try to carry out such User’s  request to Opt Out; provided, however, ATSA will not have any obligation to retrieve, and cannot prevent the further use by others (including, without limitation, ATSA Partners) of such User’s  personal identifiable information that may have been shared with others prior to the effective date of the User’s Opt Out.
If a User elect to Opt Out, and provided such User has properly delivered its Opt Out request to ATSA in accordance with this Privacy Policy, such User will no longer receive emails directly from ATSA after a commercially reasonable time from the date such User sent its  Opt Out notice to ATSA. However, ATSA does not have any obligations under, or liability arising out of, this Privacy Policy with regard to: (a) a User’s use of any other internet websites, blogs, bulletin boards, chat rooms, and similar forums which are not under ATSA’s direct control and ownership, even if the User linked to any of these forums via the ATSA Site; and (b) any other communications sent to a User by any party (including, without limitation, ATSA Partners) other than directly from ATSA. Accordingly, such User should contact such other entities (including, without limitation, ATSA Partners) directly regarding their use of  the User’s  personally identifiable information.
2. ENFORCEMENT OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY
Each User confirms and agrees that by the User’s act of using any of the ATSA Sites, including without limitation uploading any of the User’s  personal identifiable information or any other content via any ATSA Site, the User: (a) unconditionally agrees to all of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy; and (b) further agrees that no provision of this Privacy Policy (including without limitation  the Opt Out provisions of Section 1) shall limit, condition, alter, or amend, in any way whatsoever, any rights that User may have granted to ATSA pursuant to any other agreement that User may have with ATSA.
3. PROTECTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION
Except for any use by internet search engines or any use by ATSA Partners, and except as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy (including without limitation the Intended Uses noted  above in this Privacy Policy) or in any other agreement that User may have with ATSA, and subject to ATSA’s compliance with the ATSA Code of Ethics, ATSA generally does  not intentionally make available to the general public any other personally identifiable information of the User provided to ATSA in connection with User’s  use of the ATSA Site. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the transmission of personally identifiable information between the User and the ATSA Site may not be encrypted and may not be secure. While ATSA strives to protect a User’s  personal identifiable information, ATSA cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to, from, or over any ATSA Site and the User does so at the User’s own risk.
4. ACCESSING AND UPDATING USER’S  PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION
Users are solely responsible for correcting, updating, modifying or eliminating any and all of  the User’s  personally identifiable information as it appears in, and as otherwise stored or contained in, any ATSA Site. Without in any way limiting the foregoing, User acknowledges and agrees that ATSA has no duty to correct, update, modify or eliminate any of the User’s  personally identifiable information as it appears in, is stored, or is otherwise contained in, the ATSA Site.
5. LINKS TO, AND USE OF, THIRD PARTY SITES
The ATSA Site may, now or in the future, provide links or other access to Internet websites, blogs, bulletin boards, chat rooms, similar forums or other programs which are not under ATSA’s sole control and not solely owned by ATSA (collectively referred to as “Third Party Sites”) If a User clicks on a link to, or otherwise gains access to, such a Third Party Site, the User will be transported to one of these Third Party Sites. THIS PRIVACY POLICY ONLY APPLIES TO OUR “ATSA SITE” (AS DEFINED HEREIN), AND IS NOT INTENDED TO DESCRIBE THE PRIVACY POLICIES OF THIRD PARTY SITES WITH REGARD TO THEIR COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION. ATSA IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PRIVACY PRACTICES OF THIRD PARTY SITES.  IF  A USER CLICKS ON A LINK TO, OR IS SENT TO A LINK OF, OR OTHERWISE GAIN ACCESS TO, A THIRD PARTY SITE, THE USER SHOULD REVIEW THE PRIVACY STATEMENTS OR POLICIES OF SUCH THIRD PARTY SITE (IF ANY) TO DETERMINE THAT THIRD PARTY SITE'S PRACTICES WITH REGARD TO THE COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, each User agrees that if the User uses any Third Party Site in any way, the User is aware that any of  User’s  personally identifiable information that the User provides to that Third Party Site might be read, collected, or otherwise used by other users of that Third Party Site or by any other third parties, and could be used to send the User unsolicited messages. ATSA is not responsible for any personally identifiable information that User elects to submit in, or otherwise make available to, these Third Party Sites. Any link on the ATSA Site to any Third Party Site does not imply an endorsement of the privacy practices of such Third Party Site by Us, and no such Third Party Site is authorized to make any representation or warranty on our behalf.
6. NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION.
During a User’s visit to the ATSA Site, ATSA may use the User’s  Internet Protocol (“IP”) address to help ATSA administer the ATSA Site. Also, our server (or any server that ATSA engages) may place small temporary text files called “cookies” on the User’s  computer  processor or in the browser directory of  the User’s  hard drive. ATSA  may also use the User’s  IP address and/or cookies to gather non-personally identifiable demographic information, such as how many Users visited a certain part of the Site, but not to track a specific IP address to the identity of a particular individual User. A User may choose not to accept cookies by setting the User’s web browser to either refuse all cookies or to notify the User each time before a cookie is set
7. DO NOT TRACK
Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that lets web site users inform web sites or other applications that they do not want to have their online activities tracked. These ”do not track” features may also give website users other choices regarding the collection of their personal identifiable information. However, these “do not track” features and “do not track’ signals are not yet uniform. Accordingly, each User of this ATSA Site is hereby notified that this ATSA Site is not currently set up to respond to any of the User’s  “do not track” features or “do not track” signals.
8. THIS PRIVACY POLICY MAY CHANGE.
This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time and at any time by ATSA. ATSA reserves the right to change it without notice to A User.  A USER IS BOUND BY THE VERSION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY THAT IS IN EFFECT AT THE TIME THE USER USES THE PARTICULAR ATSA SITE. THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY MAY BE DIFFERENT THE NEXT TIME THE USE USES THAT ATSA SITE.  NY USE OF THE ATSA SITE BY THE USER AFTER SUCH AMENDMENT(S) SHALL BE DEEMED TO CONSTITUTE ACCEPTANCE BY THE USER OF THE AMENDMENT(S).  EACH USER SHOULD REGULARLY REVIEW AND PRINT THIS PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE USER’S  RECORDS.
If a User believe that ATSA has not complied with the policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, or if the User has any questions relating to this Privacy Policy, then the User should write to ATSA at office@atsa.com.
